# Tiberiu Goanță

**Certified Scrum Master** 

tibi.goanta@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile / AgileTB Portfolio



# **Summary**

As a **Senior Scrum Master** with **11+ years of experience** in diverse technology domains, I enable teams to become better in their Agile processes, so they can develop and deliver the best products on the market as efficiently as possible.

I've helped my clients **increase the value delivered in under 6 months** of coaching, facilitation and management by improving their projects, team collaboration and productivity.

I have **facilitated and built more than 12 teams in 6 technology industries** including banking, automotive, e-Commerce, airline ticketing, telecommunication and game development.

I am proficient in the Atlassian suite using **Jira and Confluence** and versatile with tools like Trello, Asana, Monday, ClickUp, Notion, Slack, Discord, Miro, etc.

# **Experience**



## Senior Scrum Master / Oct 2022 - Mar 2023 / Luxoft

Sabre Project / Full Remote / Distributed teams in PL, DE, UA, RO, BY

- Took Ownership and led the Agile Transformation of the Airline Ticketing department for over 6 months and successfully adapted the Spotify model to the teams.
- Split 2 large 20-person teams into 5 teams which eliminated wasted time and uncertainty.
- Increased delivery by 20% in velocity improvement from first to last Sprint.
- Coached product owners, architects and managers on the Agile Way of Working.
- From my own initiative, I held extra coaching sessions in other departments and Retrospectives with all the key stakeholders which resulted in **streamlined quarterly planning**.
- Was responsible for the wellbeing of the entire department, **syncing with leads 1:1** to improve the productivity and ways of working of the teams.



## Senior Scrum Master / Jul 2021 - Sep 2022 / Luxoft

TOGG Project / Full Remote / Distributed teams in TR, DE, UA, RO, IN

- Contributed to the continuous improvement of the Agile Way of Working and to the creation of 2 Scrum teams in the automotive industry which enabled the client to create a world class navigation solution for a new electric car.
- Facilitated the Scrum ceremonies (Planning, Daily, Refinement, Review, Retro) for both teams which resulted in **constant and predictable delivered outcomes**.
- Increased Sprint velocity and burn-down by 10% and reported progress to the client and other stakeholders with improved client satisfaction.
- Coached developers and stakeholders regarding Scrum and Agile methods, onboarded new colleagues and included their feedback into the continuous improvement process.



### Scrum Master / Jun 2020 - Jul 2021 / Deutsche Bank

Full Remote / Distributed teams in DE, RO, UK, IN, SG

- Built from scratch 2 fully remote Scrum teams as I onboarded developers, testers, product owners, and
  data analysts into the project. The teams started to deliver live software in 3 months from creation.
- Organized and coached the teams on their mastery of Agile using SAFe practices together with 20 other teams as part of the Surveillance & Regulatory Corporate Bank Department.
- Improved the Agile processes for the 2 teams which enabled them to **become cross-functional** and to deliver software products in an efficient way Sprint by Sprint with a **5% increase**.
- Successfully facilitated Scrum ceremonies, removed impediments and shielded the teams from external distractions to **maintain their velocity output**.
- Worked with the Product Owner and the development teams to set strategic direction, to solve complex and mission critical problems and to release the product on time with high quality and ensure the success of the project.
- Set up Scrum of Scrums events to actively and regularly communicate with the other teams, Scrum Masters, business partners and stakeholders to manage requirements, delivery and to mitigate risks, dependencies and impediments.



# Scrum Master & QA Lead / Jul 2018 - Jun 2020 / 1&1 Internet Development

Bucharest On-Site / Distributed teams in DE, RO

- On my own initiative I took the role of the first Scrum Master for 2 of the teams inside the shops and web applications for the WEB.DE and GMX.NET domains.
- **Increased the value delivered to the online shops** by facilitating Scrum ceremonies, estimating and planning tasks together with the teams and interacting with the Product Owner and the business side.
- Established the standards and processes inside Jira for all the Tasks, Epics, User Stories, Bugs, and other tickets which resulted in **clear workflow, improved productivity and team collaboration**.
- As a Scrum Master and a QA Lead I coordinated the implementation of Definition of Done and CI
  deployment with testing gates which improved project quality and delivery from 1 month to 1 week.
- Performed QA Lead role within the local teams by coordinating QA tasks and supporting each QA team member to grow through **regular 1:1 meetings**.
- **Created a QA Guild** for all the QA members inside the Romania and Germany teams which enabled them to self organize, discuss, share ideas and align on common topics.
- Improved QA collaboration and productivity by organizing regular syncs and technical slack days and also communicating QA specific information throughout the department in **Sprint newsletters**.



## QA Automation Engineer / Jul 2017 – Jul 2018 / rinf.tech

1&1 Internet Development Project / Bucharest On-Site / Distributed teams in DE, RO

- Executed and maintained functional and regression tests each Sprint which **increased quality delivered** in the web applications for the WEB.DE and GMX.NET domains.
- Created and updated 2 UI automated regression suites based on Java, Maven, Selenium WebDriver, Serenity and Cucumber.
- Integrated the regression suites with CI/CD automated pipelines using Gitlab CI and Docker and reduced execution time from 2 days to 4 hours.
- Ran performance tests using JMeter to test the stability of the applications and ran security tests using Burp Suite Professional which **reduced the security issues by 50%** before reaching the Security team.



## Software QA Engineer / Jan 2015 – Jun 2017 / Luxoft

Lenovo Data Center Group Project / Bucharest On-Site / Distributed teams in USA, RO, IN, CN

- As part of the IP Multicast team I created and executed automated tests on top of rack and embedded switches and on X6 and chassis servers for several networking features such as IGMP, UFP, LLDP, WRED, OSPF, IP Loopback interface.
- Tested IGMP and vLAG on Lenovo switches, measured the platforms in stress-load scenarios, which validated performance compared to 3rd party switches such as Cisco Nexus.
- Created and executed tests in a Lenovo in house automation framework using Python and created new
  APIs to integrate with automated Ixia tests which increased testing speed from 20 tests per week to
  20 tests per day.
- Reported any issue found while testing in the bug tracking application Bugzilla.



#### Software QA Engineer / Oct 2012 - Dec 2014 / Luxoft

IBM Systems & Technology Group Project / Bucharest On-Site / Distributed teams in USA, RO, IN, CN

- As part of the Virtualization Team, tested the software for embedded and top of rack networking hardware (IBM products) to ensure it functions according to specifications and client requirements.
- Tested all major releases on a broad range of data center virtualization features using functional, component, performance, system, regression and sanity tests with **testing coverage always on time**.
- Improved the testing processes and documentation with reviews each quarter.
- Reported any issue found while testing in the bug tracking applications Bugzilla & ClearQuest.



## Trainee Monitor Engineer / Jul 2012 – Sep 2012 / Telekom Romania

Bucharest On-Site / Distributed teams in RO

- Monitored the national IP infrastructure at the access, distribution and core levels.
- Investigated issues and escalated tickets to the appropriate department and dispatched field engineers.

# **Education**



#### **University Politehnica of Bucharest**

Bachelor of Science - BS Electronics, Telecommunications and Information Technology 2008 - 2012



### Certified ScrumMaster (CSM) Scrum Alliance

Issued May 2021 001195023